Md Dilshad Azam Team Lead

Email:azam.dilshad@gmail.com
Contact No: 9082939990

Carrier objective:

To be able to successfully deliver the requirements of client and be able to serve them in a way that they are fully satisfied and always strive to build an interdependent relationship with team members, clients with the help of effective personal management and effective leadership.

- 5 + years of Full Stack software development experience in the areas of .Net (C#,.Net Core, MVC) ,MERN(Mongo DB, Express,ReactJS,NodeJS),Next JS, web technologies like HTML,CSS, Tailwind , TypeScript, Java script and SQL-Server Development,Prisma,PostgresSql.
- Certified AWS Associate developer. Experience in cloud development.
- Worked on Redis and Kafka for message brokering services.
- Have sufficient Devops knowledge to do CI/CD.
- Mentored juniors, provided guidance and held the team together through effective leadership.
- Have used different design patterns(Singleton Pattern, Factory Pattern, Repository Pattern)
- Have good experience of writing stored procedures and queries in SQL server.
- Have good knowledge on multiprocessing and performance enhancements.
- Have good knowledge in Web API.
- Have worked on development of insurance products
- Have work experience in agile delivery.
- Have sound communication skill and good at understanding clients requirement.
- Team player, proactive and self motivated.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

- Working as a Team Lead in SLK Software for Regions Bank from November 2023 till date.
- Worked as a Software Engineer for CommonWealth Bank Of Australia from March 2022 till June 2022.
- Worked as a Senior Software Engineer for Inube Software Pvt. Soln. Ltd. from March 2019 till March 2022.
- Worked as an Associate Software Engineer for Accenture Software Pvt. Soln. Ltd. from September 2017 to March 2019

Educational Qualification:

Degree	CPGA/Percentage	University/School
B.Tech(2017)	71%	GGSIPU(Delhi)

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Operating system	Windows Family,Linux		
Languages	C#,Java Script (ES6),MERN(Mongo DB, Express, React JS, NodeJS)		
Microsoft Technologies	Entity Framework,.Net Core,.Net MVC,ADO.NET 2.0		
E-Commerce/Internet	HTML,CSS,JQuery,BootStrap		
Web & App Server	IIS		
RDBMS	SQL-Server 2008 and 2012		
Development Tools (GUI)	Visual Studio .Net 2008/2014,GITHUB,GITBASH,JENKINS		

PROJECTS HANDLED:

Project#1 : Banking Application

Duration : November 2023 to till date

Role : Team Member.

Technologies : .Net Core, API, React JS, Java

Script,JQuery,HTML,CSS,SQLServer212.

Tools :Visual Studio 2021, GitHub, Git, Open Shift, Harness(Next Gen)

Team size :08

Description: It is a complete banking application which caters to users helping them to do online banking with all the modern features of domestic and international payment methods. The front end written in React and the backend written in microservices.

Responsiblities:

- Involved in creating several functional components in React.
- Created the microservices api to be consumed in frontend.
- Implemented mulesoft proxies.
- Involved in writing unit test cases.
- Implemented CI/CD pipeline in GitHub Actions

Project#2 : Health Insurance Project

Duration : January 2020 to till March 2022

Role : Team Member.

Technologies : .Net Core, MVC, MongoDB, Node JS, C#, ADO.NET, Java

Script, JQuery, HTML, CSS, SQL Server 212.

Tools :Visual Studio 2019,GitHub,Git

Team size :08

Description: This project does the claims processing. When the insurer files a claim it passes through several steps of Inwarding, Document Upload, Medical Adjudication and final approval. It is a role based application which facilitates claims settlement in a short interval of time.

Responsibilities

- Implemented rule engine for speedy claim processing.
- Wrote windows Scheduler to trigger apis at defined interval or time.
- Implemented Restful services(Web ApI) to be consumed by third party system.
- Wrote optimized Stored Procedures and functions to fetch data from database.
- Implemented factory design pattern for object creation to achieve loosely coupled application.
- Created several functional Components for React Projects.
- Implemented Redux for authorization.

Project#3 : Commission Payout Application
Duration : March 2019 to till January 2020

Role : Team Member(Have handled the entire project).

Technologies: MVC, C#, ADO.NET, Java Script, JQuery, HTML, CSS, SQLServer 2012.

Tools :Visual Studio 2017,TFS

Team size :02

Description:

The application is all about Paying Commission to the agents who are generating business for the insurance company by selling policy to the customers. Depending upon the performance of the agents commission is given to them. Rules are defined based on which how much commission is supposed to be given to the agents. If the agent brings good business to insurance company they are given good incentives. If they are not giving quality business to the insurance company their incentives are less.

There is no manual intervention in this and they are automated process.

Responsibilities

- Implemented multithreading, Worked on Code optimization, Implemented Indexing of tables to reduce time of data fetch and finally was able to reduce the time of data processing from 24 hrs to 1.5 hrs.
- Implemented role based authorization and authentication in the application.
- Created Web Pages.

Project#4 : Insurance Application for Claims Processing

Duration :1st September 2017 to 5th March 2019

Role : Team Member.

Technologies :MVC,C#,ADO.NET,JQuery, Java Script,CSS,HTML,SQLServer2012

Tools :Visual Studio 2017, Github, Jenkins, Gitbash

Team size :07

Description:

The system helped in settling various claims pertaining to Different line of Business(Motor,Marine or Health). It involved various process of Inwarding, Data entry operation, Inspection/Adjudication and finally the payments. It also consisted of several AI approach to detect fraud claims.

Responsibilities:

- Involved in major and minor enhancement of the project.
- Used Entity Framework for fetching data from database
- Involved in Javascript validation for forms submission.
- Also used ADO.net and wrote stored procedures

Extracurricular Achievements

- Served the nation as a Subordinate Officer in CRPF.
- Winner of Debate Competition in CRPF.
- First Runner Up in Ultra Marathon(50k).
- Winner Of Empower Run 2019 10 k race organized in Accenture.
- First runner up of Empower Run 2018 10k race organized in Accenture.
- Declared as Fitness Champion for highest number of push ups and for doing planks for longest period amongst all participants in Accenture.

Hobbies

Running, Cycling, Swimming, Reading Books, Public speaking